Guide to the Alexander Jackson Davis Architectural Drawing Collection 1827-1884 PR 16
New-York Historical Society
- [Methodist Church, Red Hook], 94253 (Item 218a)
  framed by Jonathan Beers of Bridgeport, Conn., transported by water and overland, replaced 1893, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 113; see #217-218b
- [Mount Wollaston, for Charles Francis Adams and John Quincy Adams], 94252 (Item 379)
  Quincy (Mass.)
- [NC Hospital for the insane/Davidson College], 94251 (Item 442)
  Raleigh (N.C.), Davidson (N.C.)
  Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 114 and 117
- [New Haven Center Church?] "Pulpit, New Haven center ch." graphite LR, 94250 (Item 208b)
- [New York or Long Island Historical Society] "HIST." ink UR, 94249 (Item 055 verso)
  this drawings are more probably related to the NY Historical Society
- [North Carolina Hospital for the Insane], 94248 (Item 32)
  Raleigh (N.C.)
  partially extant, center section demolished, much altered, including additions and roof alteration.
- [North Carolina State Capitol], 94247 (Item 326 verso)
  extant. MBB questions whether this is the capitol
- [Rathbone or Raymond Residence] "Remarks" ink UL, 94246 (Item 597)
  Albany (N.Y.), Syracuse (N.Y.)
  for project identification, see note added to drawing; see also Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 110 and 115
- [Rathbone, Joel Villa, Kenwood], 94245 (Item 135)
  Albany (N.Y.)
  farmhouse, gate house, furniture, south of Albany, villa demolished, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 110; see also drawings #113, 134a-h
- [Residence, unidentified] "Second floor." ink UL, 94244 (Item 452)
- [Richards, A. C. House] Woodcliff, 94243 (Item 256)
  New York (N.Y.)
  Building demolished in 1939
- [Rotunda Plan - unidentified building], 94242 (Item 000 verso)
  see 000 recto
- [Rutherford, John House?], 94241 (Item 531 verso)
  New Jersey
  unidentified; see also drawings #514-516, 526, 531recto-534
- [Rutherford, John House], 94240 (Item 531 recto)
  unidentified, see also drawings #514-516, 526, 532-534
- [Shotwell, Jacob R. House], 94239 (Item 170 verso)
  Rahway (N.J.)
- [Unidentified public building], 94238 (Item 483)
- [Villa, Etruscan, unidentified] "West Front" ink wash, ink, graphite BM, 94237 (Item 112)
- [Villa, Tuscan], 94236 (Item 175)
- [W. Presbyterian Church Carmine St.] "horizontal Section of window. Church Greenwich full size" graphite UR, 94235 (Item 364 verso)
- 4 dwellings - double townhouses "4 dwellings" graphite UL, 94234 (Item 242)
- 751 Broadway, store "Specification for works and materials in renovating and making additions to a store, 751 Broadway, NY according to drawings A.B.C.", 94233 (Item 039 b)
- 751 Broadway, store "Specification for works and materials in renovating and making additions to a store, 751 Broadway, NY according to drawings", 94232 (Item 039 a)
- Adams, C. F. Residence, Mt. Wollaston [elevation], 94231 (Item 370)
  Drawing heavily reworked; not executed despite many later revisions and enlargements
- Alger, C. C. House "Residence of C. C. Alger Esq. Downing Place Hudson River" CM, 94230
  Newburgh (N.Y.)
  book plate?
- Alger, C. C. House "First Study for C. C. Alger. Downing Place. Newburgh" watercolor, graphite BL, 94229 (Item 260)
  see also no # print. Remodelling of A. J. Downing's villa. Demolished
- Alger, C.C. House "RESIDENCES OF C. C. ALGER, esq. DOWNING PLACE, HUDSON RIVER" NA MC, 94228 (Item 260a)
  Anderson engraver, remodeling of A. J. Downing' villa and coach house/gardener' house, demolished, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 115
- Angier, John Esq. House "House for John Angier, Esq." watercolor UR, "Principal Floor" ink LL, 94227 (Item 362 a)
  Medford (Mass.)
- Angier, John Esq. House [second floor plan], 94226 (Item 362 b)
- Angier, John Esq. House [first floor plan], 94225 (Item 362 c)
- Apartment house "Third Fourth Fifth" ink, graphite UL-UR, 94224 (Item 284b)
- Apartment house "For An Aprtment H. 50 by 90 Ft" ink, graphite BR, 94223 (Item 284a)
- Aral "Aral at Wildmont Park, N.J." watercolor, graphite BL-BR, 94222 (Item 252a)
- Aral "Longitudinal Section VIII." watercolor graphite UM-UR, 94221 (Item 252b)
- Archer, William S. House "ELK HILL PLANTATION MANSION OF WM. S. ARCHER, AMELIA, VA." ink LC; "SOUTH FRONT." watercolor LC, 94220 (Item 271a)
  Amelia County (Va.)
  remodeling, corn-and-wheat capitals on veranda, burned during the Civil War, Peck,, Alexander Jackson Davis, 114; see also #271b-d
- Archer, William S. House, Elk Hill NA, 94219 (Item 271d verso)
  remodeling, burned during the Civil War, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 114; see also drawings #271a-e
- Archer, William S. House, Elk Hill "Mansion of the Hon. Wm. S. Archer. "Elk Hill", Amelia Co. Va. 1850." ink UR, 94218 (Item 271b)
- Archer, William S. House, Elk Hill "Second Story. 38 by 90. Hon. Wm. S. Archer; Elk Hill. Va. Amelia Co. 1850. '51. '53." ink UR, 94217 (Item 271c)
- Archer, William S. House, Elk Hill "Plantation Mansion "Elk Hill" Amelia Co. Va. 1850" ink UL, 94216 (Item 271d recto)
- Archer, William S. House, Elk Hill "Plan of Principal Floor. Design C. for Wm. S. Archer. of Elk Hill. Va. 1850. first study." ink UR, 94215 (Item 271e)
  remodeling, burned during the Civil War, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 114; see also drawings #271a-d
- Art gallery "Picture Gallery or Bank" graphite MR, 94214 (Item 328 a)
- Art gallery "A Lecture Room. 60 Ft. B. Picture Balcony." ink, UL-UR, 94213 (Item 328 b)
- Art gallery, unidentified "Study for for a Picture Gallery. No. 2." graphite UC, 94212 (Item 596)
- Astor Hotel "First Study for the Beach at front", 94211 (Item 13)
- Astor Library "First Plan - Astor Library" watercolor and graphite UM, 94210 (Item 001b recto)
  see 001b verso; see also #0-10. Initial studies for Astor Library made in 1843 at request of Washington Irving, Alexander Jackson Davis, p. 53
- Astor Library "Upper Alcoves" watercolor graphite, 94209 (Item 001c recto)
  see 001a verso; see also #0-10. Initial studies made in 1843 at request of Washington Irving, A. J. Davis, American Architect, p. 53.
- Astor Place "Astor Place." Lot where the Merc Library now stands. at first intended for dwellings; then Opera" ink, graphite BM-BR, 94208 (Item 287)
- Audience hall with library "Illustrating an Audience Hall, with Library Under" ink, graphite BL-BR, 94207 (Item 001a)
  see 001c recto; see also #0-10.
- Bank "For a BanK" watercolor, UM, 94206 (Item 022a)
- Bank, unidentified "No. 1" UR graphite, 94205 (Item 313 a)
- Bank, unidentified "No 2" UR graphite, 94204 (Item 313 b)
- Bank, unidentified "FOR A BANK." ink wash LC, 94203 (Item 299)
- Barrett House, 94202 (Item 85)
- Barrett House "Second Story." ink UR, 94201 (Item 111b)
  Orange (N.J.)
  see also drawings #111a, 111c, 85, 537
- Barrett House "Principal floor." ink UR, 94200 (Item 111a)
  see also drawings #111b-c, 085, 537
- Barrett House "Barrett. High towered house" ink UR, 94199 (Item 111c recto)
  see also drawings #111a, 111b, 85, 537
- Barrett House "Barrett. Second Story. 2." ink UR, 94198 (Item 111c verso)
- Barrett House "SIMPLE COUNTRY HOUSE" watercolor LC, 94197 (Item 537)
- Barton, Coralie Livingston House, Montgomery Place, Farm Cottage "Attic." graphite UC, 94196 (Item 120a verso)
  Annandale-on-Hudson (N.Y.)
  additions to mansion (1863-64), farm cottage (1861), house (1867), extant, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118; see also drawings #120a-b, 122
- Barton, Coralie Livingston House, Montgomery Place, Farm Cottage, 94195 (Item 120b verso)
  addition to mansion (1863-64), farm cottage (1861), and house (1867), extant, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118; see also drawings #120a-c, 122
- Barton, Coralie Livingston House, Montgomery Place, Farm Cottage "EAST END, FARM HOUSE, CORA L. BARTON." ink LC, 94194 (Item 120b recto)
  additions to mansion (1863-1864), farm cottage (1861), house (1867), extant, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118; see also drawings #120a-c, 122
- Barton, Coralie Livingston House, Montgomery Place, Farm Cottage "FARM COTTAGE FOR C. L. BARTON. M. Pl." ink LC, 94193 (Item 120a recto)
  additions to mansions (1863-64), farm cottage (1861), house (1867), extant, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118; see also drawings #120a-c, 122
- Barton, Coralie Livingston House, Montgomery Place, Farm Cottage "Principal. 2." graphite UR, 94192 (Item 120c)
  additions to mansions (1863-64), farm cottage (1861), house (1867), extant, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118; see also #120a-b, 122[=120c verso]
- Barton, Coralie Livingston House, Montgomery Place, Farm Cottage "DOUBLE FARM HOUSE. Montgomery Pl." ink UR, 94191 (Item 122)
  additions to mansions (1863-64), farm cottage (1861), house (1867), extant, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 118; see also #120a-c [122=120c verso]
- Basement dwellings "Design for Small Basement Dwellings Entrance Thro' Basement", 94190 (Item 261)
- Baughman, John C. House "Baughman 1853 a Study", 94189 (Item 97)
  Detroit (Mich.)
  demolished.
- Baughman, John C. Residence and Munn, John Residence "STUDY ON BAUGHMAN AND JOHN MUNN" ink and graphite LR, 94188 (Item 96)
  Detroit (Mich.), Utica (N.Y.)
  Baughman plans (watercolored?, see #97) probably inspired Munn plans (2 floor and graphite?, see #162-3,365); Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 116
- Baum House, 94187 (Item 148 recto)
  see also verso and drawings #149 recto-verso
- Belmead, 94186 (Item 274)
  for Philip St. George Cocke, house estant some details lost
- Belmead "Principal floor of "Belmead" ink, graphite UL-UM, 94185 (Item 274)
- Belmead "Second Floor" ink UR, 94184 (Item 274c)
- Booklet of Pauper Asylum, New York, Middlesex Pauper Lunatic Asylum, London, North Carolina Hospital for the Insane "Asylum London. New York. Raleigh. From Alex J. Davis, Architect 203 W. 11th St. NY 1883", 94183 (Item 30)
- Boston Athenaeum "Library Boston" watercolor MC and LC, 94182 (Item 317)
  Boston (Mass.)
  not executed, Peck, Alexander Jackson Davis, 111
- Bowery residence and church "3 Dwellings and Large Ch." ink, graphite CL, 94181 (Item 247c)
- Bracketed cottage with ornamental veranda, unidentified, 94180 (Item 565)
- Broadway store Basement plan for Store on Broadway, 94179 (Item 39)
- Broadway store Main floor plan for Store on Broadway, 94178 (Item 039 e)
- Broadway store "Front", 94177 (Item 039 d verso)
- Broadway store Calculations for store on Broadway, 94176 (Item 039f verso)
- Broadway store Second floor plan for Store on Broadway, 94175 (Item 039 d recto)
- Broadway store, 94174 (Item 039 c)
- Brooklyn City Hall, 94173 (Item 309 i)
  competition design, not executed
- Brooklyn City Hall "Des. No. IV or VI or VIII" UL graphite, 94172 (Item 309 h)
- Brooklyn City Hall "Section Showing a Torunda or Open Area 140 Ft. Diameter. Entire Building 220 Ft." L ink, 94171 (Item 309 j)
- Brooklyn City Hall "No. IV Basement" UR, graphite, 94170 (Item 309 i)
- Brooklyn City Hall "Design No V City Hall" ink LL, 94169 (Item 309 g)
- Brooklyn City Hall "Design No I" ink, 94168 (Item 309 f)
- Brooklyn City Hall "Design No. 1 See index of Arc. Studies, G.X. No 2. is Hexagon in A" graphite, 94167 (Item 309 e recto)
- Brooklyn City Hall "Design made for the Brooklyn City Hall" ink, 94166 (Item 309 3 verso)
- Brooklyn City Hall "Plan to No IV" ink, 94165 (Item 309 d)
- Brooklyn City Hall "City Hall Brooklyn" graphite, 94164 (Item 309 c)
- Brooklyn City Hall "Study for City Hall Brooklyn" ink, 94163 (Item 309 b verso)
  competition design, not executed, folded in half to make four sections
- Brooklyn City Hall "For the Brooklyn City Hall in 1830 - 40" ink, 94162 (Item 309 b recto)
- Brooklyn City Hall "For the Brooklyn City Hall 1840" graphite, 94161 (Item 309 a)
- Brown, Lewis B. Residence [Plan], 94160 (Item 373)
- Building, seven-story, unidentified "Long Section" graphite UR, 94159 (Item 448)
- Building, two-story, unidentified, 94158 (Item 542)
- Building, unidentified, 94157 (Item 417)
- Building, unidentified, 94156 (Item 441)
- Building, unidentified, 94155 (Item 439 recto)
- Building, unidentified, 94154 (Item 439 verso)
- Building, unidentified, 94153 (Item 426)
- Building, unidentified, 94152 (Item 431)
  this drawing looks like a piece meant to be collaged onto another drawing
- Building, unidentified "C. 1." graphite UR; "PRINCIPAL FLOOR" watercolor UC-UR; "PLAN OF THE SECOND FLOOR." ink wash UL-UC, 94151 (Item 430)
- Building, unidentified elevation, 94150 (Item 579)
  see also drawing #578
- Building, unidentified, 94149 (Item 595 verso)
- Building, unidentified, 94148 (Item 408)
  drawn on verso of a piece of advertisement
- Building, unidentified, 94147 (Item 509)
- Building, unidentified, 94146 (Item 504 verso)
- Building, unidentified, 94145 (Item 518)
  estimates for costs (brick work, plastening, excavation, stone work, roof, chemney, carpenters, paintings, plumbing etc.)
- Building, unidentified, 94144 (Item 525)
- Building, unidentified, 94143 (Item 527)
  sketch
- Building, unidentified, 94142 (Item 528)
  floor plan with hexagonal room 16 feet across
- Building, unidentified, 94141 (Item 518)
- Building, unidentified [Litchfield, Edwin Clark Row Houses?], 94140 (Item 386)
  maybe related to drawings #382-383
- Burial chapel for Evergreen Cemetary "Burial Chapel. Copy for D. Evergreen Cemetry, L.I." ink UR, 94139 (Item 209a)
  Queens (New York, N/Y.)
  see also drawing #209b
- Burial chapel for Evergreen Cemetary, 94138 (Item 209a)
  see also drawing #209a
- Butler, Chas. E. House Additions "Plan of Principal floor No.2 Chas. E. Butler Study for additions to his house on Staten Island not executed", 94137 (Item 240a)
  Staten Island (New York, N.Y.)
  Not built, house burned
- Butler, Chas. E. House Additions, 94136 (Item 240b)
- Butterfield House "South Front", 94135 (Item 266a)
- Butterfield House "South Front" watercolor, graphite BM, 94134 (Item 265a)
- Butterfield House "Plan of principal floor" ink, graphite UM-UR, 94133 (Item 265b)
- Butterfield House "Principal Floor", 94132 (Item 266b)
- Butterfield House "Second Story", 94131 (Item 266c)
- Butterfield, Major General Daniel Houses, 94130 (Item 519 recto)
  skecth; see also drawings #520-524
- Butterfield, Major General Daniel Houses, 94129 (Item 519 verso)
- Butterfield, Major General Daniel Houses, 94128 (Item 520)
  4 pages letter, NY, Mai 20/65; concernes 3 houses on 87th street 20 or 19 by 40 each; see also drawings #519-524
- Butterfield, Major General Daniel Houses, 94127 (Item 521 recto)
- Butterfield, Major General Daniel Houses, 94126 (Item 521 verso)
  list of requirements desired about watercloset, kitchen, stairs, heater, fire place, cellar, etc; see also drawings #519-524
- Butterfield, Major General Daniel Houses, 94125 (Item 522)
  see also drawings #519-524
- Butterfield, Major General Daniel Houses, 94124 (Item 523 recto)
  sketch; see also drawings #519-524
- Bysell or Prisell, J. W. Villa "First Study for a Villa" ink LR, 94123 (Item 117)
- Calculations, unidentified, 94122 (Item 427 recto)
- Calculations, unidentified, 94121 (Item 427 verso)
- Chambers, James Residence, Project for a Highland Villa "Highland Villa to be built of stone near West Point", 94120 (Item 368)
  West Point (N.Y.)
  not executed
- Chapel "Design for a Small Chapel Estimated at $1000" ink, watercolor, graphite CM, 94119 (Item 194)
  border
- Chapel or country church, Gothic, unidentified, 94118 (Item 507 recto)
  see also verso
- Chapel or country church, Gothic, unidentified, 94117 (Item 507 verso)
  see also recto
- Chapel or country church, Gothic, unidentified, 94116 (Item 504 recto)
- Chapel, Gothic, unidentified "Design for a chapel." ink LC, 94115 (Item 226)
  see also drawings #224a-c
- Chapin House "Design for Cahpin, Navesink", 94114 (Item 86)
- Church on 4th Avenue, 94113 (Item 181b verso)
- Church on 4th Avenue "Front." watercolor, graphite BM, 94112 (Item 182a)
- Church on 4th Avenue, 94111 (Item 182c recto)
- Church on 4th Avenue "Section looking towards Pulpit" CM "Section looking from pulpit." LM ink and graphite, 94110 (Item 183a)
- Church on 4th Avenue, 94109 (Item 183c recto)
- Church on 4th Avenue, 94108 (Item 183c verso)
  for drawings probably related to this project, see also #[600-603], 5/14/98 MBB (NL)
- Church on 4th Avenue "Square Plan" ink, graphite UM "Greek Cross" ink, graphite BM, 94107 (Item 186a)
- Church on 4th Avenue "Principal Floor" ink, graphite UM, 94106 (Item 185b)
- Church on 4th Avenue "On Fourth Av" ink, graphite BM, 94105 (Item 181a)
- Church on 4th Avenue, 94104 (Item 182b)
- Church on 4th Avenue "Fourth Avenue." ink, graphite BM, 94103 (Item 181b recto)
  drawing reworked at a later date, for drawings probably related to this project, see #[600]-[603], 5/14/98 MBB (NL)
- Church on 4th Avenue, 94102 (Item 182c verso)
- Church on 4th Avenue "Gallery Floor" ink, graphite BM, 94101 (Item 184)
- Church on 4th Avenue "Section from Street Door to Pulpit", 94100 (Item 185a)
- Church, [Grace Church], unidentified, 94099 (Item 227b)
  identified as Grace Church by Roger Hale Newton in "Town and Davis Architectes" plate 46, see also drawing #227a (same drawing paper)
- Church, [Grace Church], unidentified "SKETCH OF SOUTH SIDE" ink wash LC, 94098 (Item 227a)
  identified as Grace Church by Roger Hale Newton in "Town and Davis Architectes" plate 46, see also drawing #227b (same drawing paper)
- Church, castelated Ecclesiastical, 94097 (Item 231)
- Church, castlelated Ecclesiastical "Castlelated Ecclesiastical" graphite UR, 94096 (Item 230)
- Church, circular "C" graphite UL; "No. 2" graphite UR, 94095 (Item 457)
  see also drawings #456, 458 and 459
- Church, circular "C" graphite UL; "No. 4" graphite UR, 94094 (Item 458)
  see also drawings # 456, 457 and 459
- Church, circular "C" graphite UL; "No. 1 to 5" graphite UC; "No. 1" graphite UR, 94093 (Item 459)
  see also drawings # 456-458
- Church, circular, 94092 (Item 460 recto)
- Church, circular, 94091 (Item 460 verso)
- Church, circular, 94090 (Item 464)
  calculation in graphite on verso, UL; "2' train for Fremont." verso, graphite UC-UR
- Church, circular, 94089 (Item 465 verso)
- Church, circular, 94088 (Item 465 recto)
  see also drawing #456
- Church, circular, unidentified, 94087 (Item 443a)
  see also drawings #443b recto and verso
- Church, circular, unidentified, 94086 (Item 443b recto)
  see also drawings #443a and 443b verso
- Church, circular, unidentified, 94085 (Item 443b verso)
  see also drawings #443b recto and 443a
- Church, collegiate, unidentified, 94084 (Item 204a)
  see also drawing #203
- Church, Gothic, 94083 (Item 189)
- Church, Gothic "Long. Section. 100 ft." graphite BM, 94082 (Item 234 verso)
- Church, Gothic, 94081 (Item 232)
- Church, Gothic, 94080 (Item 233)
- Church, Gothic, 94079 (Item 234 recto)
- Church, Gothic and castleated Ecclesiastical, unidentified "Castleated Ecclesiastical." ink UL, 94078 (Item 200)
- Church, Gothic, unidentified, 94077 (Item 198a)
  see also drawing #198b
- Church, Gothic, unidentified, 94076 (Item 225)
- Church, Gothic, unidentified, 94075 (Item 198b)
  see also drawing #198a; project similar to the Village Church in trumbull, CT
- Church, Gothic, unidentified, 94074 (Item 199)
- Church, Gothic, unidentified "Elevation of the West side." ink LC, 94073 (Item 207a)
  see also drawings #207b-e, 211
- Church, Gothic, unidentified Section, shewing Pulpit, and window." ink UC, 94072 (Item 207)
  see also drawings #207a-e, 211
- Church, Gothic, unidentified "LONGITUDINAL SECTION." ink wash LC, 94071 (Item 207c)
- Church, Gothic, unidentified "TRANVERSE SECTION" ink wash LC, 94070 (Item 207b)
- Church, Gothic, unidentified "SIDE." ink LL, 94069 (Item 207e)
  alterations visible; 2 sketches on verso; see also drawings #207a-d, 211
- Church, Gothic, unidentified, 94068 (Item 204b)
- Church, Gothic, unidentified, 94067 (Item 506)
- Church, Gothic, unidentified, 94066 (Item 503 recto)
- Church, Gothic, unidentified, 94065 (Item 503 verso)
- Church, Gothic, unidentified "Drawing No. 6. for a Church, St. Isl." ink LL, 94064 (Item 210)
- Church, octagonal suburban, unidentified, 94063 (Item 197b)
- Church, octogonal "FIRST FLOOR." ink wash UL; "SECOND FLOOR" ink wash UR, 94062 (Item 469)
- Church, octogonal "Octagon Interior" graphite UL-UC, 94061 (Item 197a)
  see also drawing #194
- Church, semi-circular, 94060 (Item 461)
- Church, suburban Etruscan, unidentified, 94059 (Item 206)
- Church, unidentified, 94058 (Item 193)
- Church, unidentified [plan and perspective], 94057 (Item 361 a)
- Church, unidentified "Study for Scrabble" graphite UR, 94056 (Item 361 b)
- Church, unidentified "Section Front to Rear" ink, graphite BM, 94055 (Item 191)
- Church, unidentified, 94054
- Church, unidentified, 94053 (Item 190)
- Church, unidentified [Window Details], 94052 (Item 192)
  details unusual type of drawing for Davis
- Church, unidentified, 94051
- Church, unidentified "Variety of A & B" "Circular as No I" graphite UL-UR, 94050
- Church, unidentified, 94049
- Church, unidentified, 94048
- Church, unidentified, 94047 (Item 489)
- Church, unidentified, 94046 (Item 361 c)
  inscpt con't weight diamond 1 1/2 thick itm. glass. Siding 10 to 12 in wide tongued and groved joint fillette 2 1/2 thick. bevilled on edges. con't
- Church, unidentified "Rear" "Section East En." watercolor, graphite LL-LR, 94045 (Item 361 c)
  wm: JL 1805
- Church, unidentified, 94044
- Church, unidentified, 94043
- Church, unidentified, 94042 (Item 213)
- Church, unidentified, 94041 (Item 212 verso)
- Church, unidentified, 94040 (Item 212 recto)
- Church, unidentified "DESIGN" ink wash, ink LC, 94039 (Item 219)
  see also drawings #214a-b, 215, 216, 217, 218a-b
- Church, unidentified "Plan No. 1." ink LR, 94038 (Item 485)
  see also drawings #484 recto-verso, 485-488; 224a-c and 226 (Village Church), 227a-b (Grace Church?); small sketch on verso
- Church, unidentified "Basement." ink UR, 94037 (Item 484 verso)
  see also drawings #484 recto-488, 224a-c and 226 (Village Church), 227a-b (Grace Church?)
- Church, unidentified "Principal floor." ink LL; "Gallery floor." ink LR, 94036 (Item 484 recto)
  see also drawings #484 verso-488, 224a-c and 226 (Village Church), 227a-b (Grace Church?)
- Church, unidentified, 94035 (Item 486)
  see also drawings #484 recto-verso, 485-488, 224a-c and 226 (Village Church), 227a-b (Grace Church?)
- Church, unidentified, 94034 (Item 487)
- Church, unidentified "Lonng Section No. 8" graphite LR, 94033 (Item 488)
- Church, unidentified, 94032 (Item 205)
- Church, unidentified, 94031 (Item 202)
  sketch in graphite on verso
- Church, unidentified, 94030 (Item [605])
- Church, unidentified, 94029 (Item [606])
- Church, unidentified, 94028 (Item [607])
- Church, unidentified, 94027 (Item [608 recto])
- Church, unidentified, 94026 (Item [608 verso])
- Church, unidentified, 94025 (Item [609])
- Church, unidentified, 94024 (Item [610])
- Church, unidentified, 94023 (Item 490)
  notes regarding basement rooms of a church, for sexton's apartment, library, lecture room, coal and furnace rooms, part of a plan sketch on verso
- Church, unidentified, 94022 (Item 491)
- Church, unidentified, 94021 (Item 496)
- Church, unidentified, 94020 (Item 493)
- Church, unidentified, 94019 (Item 494 recto)
- Church, unidentified, 94018 (Item 495)
- Church, unidentified "Section with low roof." graphite LC, 94017 (Item 498)
  two small sketches on verso
- Church, unidentified, 94016 (Item 499)
- Church, unidentified, 94015 (Item 497)
  "not A. J. Davis (Mrs Jane Davies 6/27/61)" verso, graphite LL-LR
- Church, unidentified, 94014 (Item 508 verso)
- Church, unidentified, 94013 (Item 508 recto)
- Church, unidentified, 94012 (Item 505)
  section showing the end wall of a pointed roofed church, indicating the placement of a large stained glass window or an alter painting
- Church, unidentified, 94011 (Item 517 verso)
- Church, unidentified "CROSS SECTION." ink LC, 94010 (Item 513)
- Church, unidentified, 94009 (Item 517 recto)
- Church, unidentified, 94008 (Item 494 verso)
- Church, window design, 94007 (Item 235)